import random

ques = [
    {
        "question": "Who is the ICC ODI Cricketer of the year for 2019?",
        "options": ["Virat Kohli", "Stive Smith", "Rohit Sharma", "Joe Root"],
        "answer": "Rohit Sharma"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who claimed the purple cap for highest wicket taker in IPL 2019?",
        "options": ["Dwane Bravo", "Imran Tahir", "Jasprit Bumrah", "Harshal Patel"],
        "answer": "Imran Tahir"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who set a new record for most number of sixes by an individual in an ODI innings?",
        "options": ["Rohit Sharma", "Glenne Phillips", "Eoin Morgan","Liam Livingston"],
        "answer":"Eoin Morgan"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who become the first cricketer to win three top ICC honours in the same year?",
        "options":["Virat Kohli","Kane Willamson","Babar Azam", "Ben Stokes"],
        "answer":"Virat Kohli"
    },
    {
        "question" : "Who was the ICC emerging player of the year 2018?",
        "options": ["Suryakumar Yadav", "Rishabh Pant", "Ishan Kishan", "Ravi Bishnoi"],
        "answer": "Rishabh Pant"
    },
    
    {
        "question": "When was the Ashes first played?",
        "options": ["1872", "1877", "1882", "1887"],
        "answer": "1882"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who won the first ever Cricket World Cup in 1975?",
        "options": ["Australia", "England", "India", "West Indies"],
        "answer": "West Indies"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the largest cricket stadium in the world?",
        "options": ["Edan Gardens", "Melbourne Cricket Club", "Lords","Narendra Modi Stadium"],
        "answer":"Narendra Modi Stadium"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many ways are there of getting out?",
        "options":["8","9", "10","11"],
        "answer":"10"
    },
    {
        "question" : "How long is the wicket on a cricket pitch?",
        "options": ["18 yards", "20 yards", "22 yards", "24 yards"],
        "answer": "22 yards"
    },
    
    
    {
        "question": "Who did England beat in the final of the 2019 Cricket World Cup?",
        "options": ["Australia","India", "New Zealand", "South Africa"],
        "answer": "South Africa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which fast bowler has taken the most test wickets?",
        "options": ["Stuart Broad","Dale Steyn","Glenn McGrath","James Anderson"],
        "answer": "James Anderson"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the nickname of Sachin Tendulkar?",
        "options": ["The Little Master", "Superman", "The Wall","God of Cricket"],
        "answer":"The Little Master"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Australian player has scored the most test runs?",
        "options":["Steve Waugh","Don Bradman","Ricky Ponting", "Matthew Hayden"],
        "answer":"Ricky Ponting"
    },
    {
        "question" : "The first official international match of cricket was held in 1844 between...",
        "options": ["Eng & Aus", "Ind & Pak", "USA & Can", "End & Ind"],
        "answer": "USA & Can"
    },
    
    {
        "question": "Who is the first batsman to cross 10,000 runs in tests?",
        "options": ["Sunil Gavaskar", "Sachin Tendulkar", "Allan Border", "Brian Lara"],
        "answer": "Sunil Gavaskar"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the only batsman to record 400 runs in an international Test match?",
        "options": ["Steve Smith", "WG Grace", "Don Bradman", "Brian Lara"],
        "answer": "Brian Lara"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which player has scored the most ducks in international cricket?",
        "options": ["Muttiah Muralitharan", "James Anderson", "Courtney Walsh","Bret Lee"],
        "answer":"Muttiah Muralitharan"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who bowled the fastest delivery ever of 100.2mph?",
        "options":["Brett Lee","Shoaib Akhtar", "Shaun Tait","Jeffrey Thompson"],
        "answer":"Shoaib Akhtar"
    },
    {
        "question" : "What is the name of the cricket bible?",
        "options": ["Willsden Cricketers Almanack", "Willsden Cricketers Handbook", "Wisden Cricketers Handbook", "Wisden Cricketers Almanack"],
        "answer": "Wisden Cricketers Almanack"
    },
]